<Document>
  # Diona

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDiona" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  They can't wear shoes, but are not slowed by Kudzu.
  They get hungry and thirsty slower.
  Their "blood" is normal water and can't be metabolised from Iron.
  Being plants, Weed Killer poisons them, while Robust Harvest heals them (but not without risk when overused!)

<<<<<<< HEAD
  Они переносят [color=#1e90ff]на 30% меньше тупого урона и на 20% меньше slash урона[/color],
  но [color=#ffa500]на 50% больше урона от тепла, и на 20% больше шокового урона, и они могут легко
<<<<<<< HEAD
  загореться, когда получают достаточное количество урона от *любого* источника тепла.[/color]
=======
  They take [color=#1e90ff]30% less Blunt damage and 20% less Slash damage[/color];
  but [color=#ffa500]50% more Heat damage, 20% more Shock damage, and they can easily
  catch on fire when receiving enough Heat damage from *any* source.[/color]
>>>>>>> parent of 5c9111000f (перевод GuideBook'a про расы)
=======
  загорается, когда получают достаточное количество урона от *любого* источника тепла.[/color]
>>>>>>> parent of 7cd4322061 (маленькие правки в переводе)

  ## Make Like A Tree And Leave
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FloraTree06" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Being exposed to too much Robust Harvest will cause a Diona to grow out of control, turning into an immobile tree (dropping all their equipment).
  Cutting down the tree will "restore" the Diona to their mobile state.

  ## Diona Nymphs
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDionaNymph" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDionaNymph" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDionaNymph" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  After death, a Diona can voluntarily destroy their own body, releasing their "internal organs" as three Nymphs,
  with the player taking control of the Brain Nymph.
  It can talk but has no hands or inventory, and can't do much.

  After 10 minutes, a Nymph can reform into a whole Diona. This will be a new randomised body with a random name,
  and there will be little to no evidence beyond their word about who they were before.


</Document>
